[KIVIA] Thanks to the hero unit
and their dragoon's attack,
we narrowly managed
to fend off the assassins.
Still, my network of deployed
Holy Knights was gutted,
and nearly half of them
perished.
It was a sneak attack designed
to isolate us and the goddess.
Their execution was flawless.
Sounds as if you're implying
that we might have a traitor
in our midst.
If we can't trust
our own allies,
we have no hope
of prevailing.
My sniper unit
was massacred.
Nearly all of them
were picked off.
[RAJIT] I suggest we limit
Goddess Teoritta's
protective detail
to only those we trust most.
-That way--
-I trust no one.
-[all gasp]
-[grunts]
The concept of "trust"
is downright laughable
at this point.
We should even be skeptical
of everyone in this room.
-[grunting]
-[Rajit scoffs]
And I can't think of anyone
we should trust less
than a penal hero.
This at least warrants
an investigation.
You should contact
the Twelfth Order
of the Holy Knights.
Though they specialize
in intelligence,
they strictly remain hidden
from the public eye.
There's no chance
of winning this fight
if we don't know
who might betray us.
Can we at least agree on that?
After careful consideration
I'd like to solicit the opinion
of the special advisor
who has joined us today.
High Priest Marlen,
what's your take?
[MARLEN] Hmm... fascinating.
As I've only just arrived
from the First Capital,
it's difficult to say.
Who we can trust is a matter
of grave importance.
No one present
is above scrutiny,
including myself.
Yet, to be frank,
I doubt the intelligence unit
will come to our aid.
How go the interrogations,
Patausche?
Not well, I am afraid.
Most of the thugs we took alive
were adventurers for hire
without any useful intel.
I regret that we failed
to capture the assassins.
Let's not despair.
You needn't shoulder the blame.
It isn't yours alone.
Try not to stew in
your own regret.
It will not improve
our situation.
Sound advice, Uncle.
Thank you.
Always so stiff, like a board.
That is your
defining characteristic.
-[XYLO] Your Eminence.
-[MARLEN] Hm?
Xylo! Be quiet!
What I have to say
should be of use.
It's imperative.
Otherwise, I would never
interrupt a man of your status.
[Marlen chuckles]
An assertive tone delivering
words of conciliation.
-Patausche...
-[KIVIA] Uh?
[MARLEN]...you could
learn from this man.
[KIVIA] Right, understood.
[MARLEN] You have
my attention, Hero Xylo.
Please enlighten us
with your insight.
[XYLO] Eminence, we should start
by investigating the middleman.
Such as those
in the Adventurers Guild.
♪
[XYLO] Lideo Sodrick.
So I take it this guy's
the guildmaster?
[SIENA] They say
an ancestor of his
founded a private army
to take down the pirates
plaguing Korio Bay.
And that's how
the guild came to be.
It's a nice little
bedtime story.
But it was probably
just a turf war
between wannabe pirates.
Well, be that as it may be,
this Lideo Sodrick
is a big deal.
The history
of the Sodrick's Shell region
and that of the
Adventurers Guild
are one and the same.
[footsteps]
-[VENETIM] Back at last.
-[XYLO] Huh?
Any cause for concern?
Huh? What do you mean?
[VENETIM] Well, it's just...
I figured they might have
saddled us
with a new punishment
or some such.
-[snoring]
-[BOTH] Uh?
[snores]
No need to worry.
It was all surprisingly
reasonable.
You don't say.
Problem?
Don't tell me
you're nursing the dream
of making a pass
at that sniper lady.
Of course not!
It isn't anything of the sort.
I...
Actually...
Forget I said anything.
So dramatic.
[Dotta groans]
Help me pick our mission's crew.
I'll give you a few pointers
while we're at it.
How generous.
But I assure you I don't need
any such advice.
[Xylo chuckles]
It has nothing to do
with romance.
I swear,
it's completely unrelated.
[LIDEO] I'm appalled
by your utter failure.
We weren't expecting a dragon,
and the heroes
were much stronger
than our intel
led us to believe.
By the way, that man
is an amateur.
You should take him off the job
or kill him where he stands.
Are you referring to me?
I had stumbled across Boojum
at a gambling house I oversee.
The place was drenched in blood.
Ten adventurers there
decided to gang up on him.
He killed every last one.
If he's such an amateur,
teach him what he needs to know.
[SHIJI BAU] Mm... He'll make
things even harder.
I'll need a bigger payday
for all that.
[Lideo scoffs]
Claiming the enemy's too strong
is an excuse to beg for money.
I see your game.
You're deliberately trying
to provoke me.
Big brother,
this woman is a wild dog.
A masterless beast
is dangerous.
[LIDEO] Iri, stand down.
I'll be fine.
[LIDEO] Shiji Bau, you're in
the Adventurers Guild now,
not the military.
If you quit early, you won't get
your final payout.
[grunts] This better be
a third of what's on the way.
I'll hire my own people.
Pros, for a change.
You dare?
[BOOJUM] I'd also like
a small pay increase.
I would like to purchase
another book.
I quite enjoy this writer
Altoyard Comette.
He's a rather brilliant poet.
[IRI] Brother,
do you think they can do it?
That is not something you need
to worry yourself about.
Do you sense someone's
presence out there?
[birds chirping]
[snores softly]
♪
[yawns]
[XYLO] Huh?
I'm not used to
seeing you up this early.
Guessing Neely kicked you
out of the stables?
-She did.
-[XYLO] Huh?
She's got a jealous streak,
and caught me spending time
with another dragon.
But it wasn't even like that.
Just drop it.
It's too early to listen
to you two bicker.
You guys
just take any excuse
to pick a fight with each other.
That's an exaggeration.
No, it isn't.
You're like powder kegs
of rage and violence
always on the verge
of exploding.
-I don't get why they don't...
-Are those three heroes?
...at least put you
on different meal schedules.
I recognize the shifty one.
It's Xylo Forbartz.
[DOTTA] Where's Teoritta?
Did you ditch her?
She's still sleeping.
Besides, I can't let her hear
what I'm about to say.
Uh-oh, I know that look.
You're gonna try and make me
do something.
You're right.
And it's something
really dangerous, yeah?
And way too dangerous
for the little goddess
to tag along.
Well done.
We're on the same page.
[Dotta groans]
You should be excited about it.
You'll get to walk around town
without shackles.
[DOTTA]
That doesn't mean anything.
Heard Tsav's right arm
got mangled in a fight
during his leisurely stroll
in town.
[XYLO] That's true,
and he should thank his
lucky stars it was just an arm.
[DOTTA] I'm scared to ask,
but what's the plan?
[XYLO] We'll start
by infiltrating
the Adventurers Guild.
[DOTTA]
But wouldn't Rhyno make
a much better fake adventurer
than me?
He used to actually
be one, right?
[XYLO] Not an option.
He's locked up at the moment,
and he's much too unpredictable
for this mission.
[SOLDIER]
Couldn't agree more.
Why not an ace liar
like Venetim, huh?
He's with His Majesty
at the repair shop.
Seems they finally found
the king a replacement leg.
-There's gotta be someone else.
-[objects clattering]
[JAYCE]
If Dotta won't go, I'll do it.
Got nothin' better to do.
Whoa! You mean it?
Well, then...
Dotta, I need
your unique skillset.
[sighs] I give up.
[scoffs] You had better not
stir up any trouble for Dotta.
He gave his arm
to feed a hungry dragon.
That's how incredible
of a human being he is.
I'm not even sure
I could make the sacrifice.
[Dotta groans]
You have
an unconventional admirer.
I don't wanna talk about it.
Go on. Tell me everything.
How do you plan
to infiltrate the guild?
[XYLO] It's simple.
♪
[Dotta] Uh...
[Xylo grunts]
[KIVIA] Hmm.
Is there a problem, Xylo?
Do you think
I look mannish again?
Say it. I dare you.
[Dotta grunts nervously]
[Xylo sighs]
No. The dress suits you.
You're the spitting image
of a young noblewoman,
with a string of suitors
fawning over her.
[Kivia gasps]
I despise empty flattery!
You can't compliment your way
to my good side.
That will never work.
I am indomitable.
Glad to hear it.
Now then, what's our reason
for hiring them?
[Kivia clears throat]
[KIVIA]
For such an establishment,
requesting faerie hunting
might work.
And here I thought that was
the military's job.
We could ask them to take out
some bandits.
Can we not minimize
the scale of violence
at least a little bit?
Bandit hunting may have worked
if we were out in the sticks,
but instead, we're in Ioff City.
[KIVIA] Why don't you
go ahead and tell us
your brilliant suggestion?
[DOTTA] Hmm.
Well, maybe, you're
a cold nobleman's wife.
And you're her secret lover.
-[KIVIA] I'm what?
-[XYLO] Huh?
And you're plotting
to get her husband murdered.
Any nobles out there
you want gone, for good?
[CONFESSOR]
Defendant: Dotta Luzulas,
you've managed to amass
over a thousand criminal acts
on your record.
[DOTTA] Uh...
[CONFESSOR] Yet, you've been
brought before us today
to answer for just one of them.
While escaping
the castle dungeon
in which you were confined,
you attempted to steal
a dragon from the stables.
[DOTTA] Uh, wait,
something's not right.
-[CONFESSOR] Elaborate.
-[DOTTA] What about him?
I would have thought he was
the biggest part of my crime.
[CONFESSOR]
To whom are you referring?
You know, I mean
the crown prince!
[NOBLE 1] What's he saying
about the crown prince?
[NOBLE 2] Why drag
His Highness into this?
You're not listening.
That little boy asked me
to save his life.
I'm not lying!
He told me he'd been
locked up in the castle,
that he needed to escape.
So I swiped the dragon
to help him break free and--
[CONFESSOR]
I've heard enough of your lies.
[Dotta gasps]
[CONFESSOR]
Your fantastical assertion
that the crown prince
spoke to you
is unequivocally false.
As is your claim that he
attempted to escape the castle.
No. There's gotta be
some mistake.
It was just after
I broke out of my cell.
I know it was the First Prince
of the Federated Kingdom.
He was only ten or so,
and the boy was terrified.
He said his family changed.
That the king wasn't behaving
like himself.
-And I think the chancellor--
-[CONFESSOR] Silence!
You've said your piece.
[DOTTA] No, wait.
There's something going on
with the royal family!
It's all true!
Why else would the crown prince
ask a thief for help?
A two-bit scumbag like me.
I'm... nothing. Nobody.
[CONFESSOR] I said be silent!
But even an actual lowlife
like me has a conscience.
There aren't
a whole lot of people
who can draw it out of me.
But when I see someone
weaker than I am,
like the prince was
in that moment,
I just wanna help them,
like anyone would.
[screams]
None of this is right.
Lock me up. Fine.
But someone has to
save the prince!
I beg you.
Someone help the prince
before it's too late!
[CONFESSOR] We cannot continue
the trial like this.
[BAILIFF] Lord Confessor,
I believe death would be
a reasonable sentence
in this case?
[CONFESSOR] Yes,
that's certainly true.
But an even harsher punishment
has already been approved
for the guilty party.
[BAILIFF] May I ask by whom?
[CONFESSOR]
That suggestion was made
by the Central Noble Alliance.
The decision is final.
[DOTTA] Monsters!
I swear I'll steal the prince
no matter what!
[CONFESSOR] Dotta Luzulas,
you are hereby sentenced
to serve as a hero.
[Dotta sighs]
Really don't wanna be here.
But I guess I've got no choice.
[footsteps]
[MAN 1]
Hey, check out my wares!
[MAN 2]
You want a drag?
-[MAN 1] They're ignoring us.
-[MAN 2] Swine.
Well, this is unpleasant.
[coughs]
[lecherous chuckling]
[XYLO] It's called
"Dragon's Breath."
You can thank Jayce
for its popularity.
They are brazenly
breaking the law.
[XYLO] I'm curious.
What made you
want to join the military?
Why ask?
You're from a Temple family
with a large domain.
It doesn't make sense
to put your neck on the line.
Guess not.
[KIVIA] Both, my mother
and father are priests.
They carried out
important duties
for the Temple
earning them certain benefits.
[XYLO] "Benefits."
Noble Priests seeking influence,
cashing in on their faith.
Right.
And not always through
aboveboard methods
like donations.
I hated that about them
and wanted to walk
a different path.
So I joined the military,
hoping to make my own way,
through my own hard work.
[XYLO] Hm? Kivia?
This training sword
is the first I ever owned.
My uncle bought it for me.
I wanted my own future,
secured with nothing more
than my own talent.
My uncle has supported me
in that endeavor, always.
[clears throat]
Your turn to share.
Let's see. So, um...
-Your fiancée--
-[DOTTA] Xylo!
I finished scouting the guild.
[XYLO] That was fast.
Good work.
[KIVIA] Honestly,
maybe a little too fast.
The security over there
seems pretty tight.
I think I spotted
around 20 guards.
[XYLO] Less than expected.
There's more.
I saw a bunch of kids around.
Little assassins or something.
Children?
That's heinous.
[XYLO]
I've heard the rumors.
They take in orphans and
raise them into loyal soldiers
who do their bidding.
All of that aside,
you really want me
to kidnap the guildmaster
while you're distracting
everyone?
You realize
that stealing people
has never gone
very well for me?
Figure it out.
Ready?
You are the daughter
of a wealthy nobleman.
And I'm your secret lover.
Sure! No problem!
Leave it to me!
[Xylo grunts]
[XYLO] Not so rough.
[IRI] He appears to be
that penal hero, Xylo Forbartz.
There's a woman with him, too.
She's clearly a Holy Knight.
Xylo Forbartz, huh?
That isn't good.
Although, if we play
our cards right,
we might be able
to take him in alive.
Got it. I will find an opening.
Bring Shiji Bau and the rest.
Just in case,
wake up Duhrsami.
Capture or kill them.
We won't fail.
[door closes]
[fire crackling]
All of this is for my family.
[indistinct chatter]
[receptionist yawning]
-How's it goin'?
-No complaints here.
[RECEPTIONIST] Mmm?
There's someone
I want to make disappear.
[RECEPTIONIST] Huh?
[KIVIA] I want the best.
Someone with
a lot of experience.
I see. And you would be...
You can call me Madleen, Miss.
Don't ask for my family name.
Right.
[RECEPTIONIST] Very well,
I assume you have a reference?
So are you going
to take the job or aren't you?
Tell me.
Miss Madleen,
we don't accept jobs
from just anyone
who walks in the door.
I apologize.
My lady is quite sheltered.
This is all rather new to her.
We don't have a reference,
but we're desperate.
At the least,
we need to leave town.
Without being traced.
So hypothetically speaking,
who do you want killed?
A pesky nobleman.
You know the Hystead family?
Bridge-keepers of Ginai?
I don't.
We are having trouble
with a third son
from one of their
branch families.
I had the misfortune
of marrying into that family.
But then this man, and I...
We pledged body and soul
to each other
beneath a sacred hagra tree!
[RECEPTIONIST] Oh.
[KIVIA] That's why I want
my husband killed,
so I am free to live out my days
with my lover.
Yes! Even if that means
running away together!
Got it. Just give me a minute,
all right? [sighs]
I've got a bad feeling.
[KIVIA] I think they suspect
we're up to something.
[XYLO] Yeah,
that much is obvious.
-[KIVIA] This is bad. What now?
-[indistinct chatter]
-[RECEPTIONIST] Truly doubt it.
-[XYLO] Here's a thought.
Raise hell.
[KIVIA] How so?
[XYLO] We'll stir up
some trouble and cause chaos,
like setting a fire
to rob a place.
Although in our case,
we're here to steal
Lideo Sodrick.
[KIVIA] What? That plan is
absurdly reckless!
But we're still doing it.
Starting with them!
[XYLO] Uh...
You did request someone skilled
now, didn't you?
-[Xylo gasps]
-It's you.
Hello, Miss Renzari.
It would seem we have
an enamored noblewoman
and her paramour. Am I right?
[Kivia and Xylo grunt softly]
[FRENCI]
May we borrow a room upstairs?
♪
You are such a mess, Xylo.
[grunts] I had a feeling
you would say that.
You're also stupid.
If I hadn't stepped in
to bail you out,
you two would have
undoubtedly been arrested.
[XYLO] You're wrong.
For your information,
we were just about
to cause a commotion,
-so there...
-[KIVIA] True.
Then our ally was to sneak in,
and secure us the evidence
that we need.
I'm curious.
Are you with the Holy Knights?
Captain of the Thirteenth Order
of the Holy Knights.
Patausche Kivia.
I would prefer if you
stopped indulging my fiancé.
Seeing as how he's foolish,
lacking education, boorish,
as well as thoughtless...
I don't need an outsider
egging him on.
[KIVIA] An outsider?
That's quite rich.
You're the outsider
to this plan.
[FRENCI] I am his fiancée.
We must face
all of life's trials together.
That's a sorry excuse!
Here we go.
I had a feeling
your personalities
were doomed to clash,
but not like this.
What? Why would you say that?
What's wrong
with our personalities?
[FRENCI] You always come
to the most asinine conclusions.
Is there no brain
between your ears?
[KIVIA] No. If only it were
that simple.
His mind is incapable
of accurately judging others.
[FRENCI] I agree.
His observational skills
are on par with a susubana mole.
[KIVIA] I would go so far
as to say your average tree
is smarter than him.
[XYLO] Can you please stop
bonding over insulting me?
We've got a serious situation
on our hands.
That's better.
Now, why are you here?
[FRENCI] I'm investigating,
disguised as an adventurer.
I was on the verge
of finally making contact
with Lideo Sodrick
until you arrived.
[XYLO] Sorry we messed that up
for you.
Although, perhaps
we could just combine our...
-[knocks on door]
-[GIRL] Excuse the interruption.
The Guildmaster would like
to speak with you
about your job request.
[Xylo chuckles]
Frenci, feel free to back out.
You jest.
The very notion disgusts me.
I knew this would end with us
stirring things up.
-[sword slashes]
-[gasps]
[screams]
Little lout.
Mind your manners.
[mercenary grunting]
Drop something?
[mercenary gasps]
[all yelling]
[grunts]
[all screaming]
[Xylo laughs]
We caused some solid chaos.
This isn't how I foresaw
the mission going.
My goodness.
You're going through with it.
Right.
We have a chance
to smoke out Lideo Sodrick,
and clean up the town
while we're at it.
Seriously?
Think of it as our civic duty.
No way this turns out well.
[♪ closing theme song playing]